It’s Professor Dave, I want to tell you
about superlatives.
There are certain things that the Italian
language does that are fun and unique, like
the altered words we learned before.
Another such construct is the way Italian
uses superlatives.
It often does this by adding a suffix to a
particular adjective.
But before we see these, let’s distinguish
between two types of superlatives.
There is the absolute superlative, and the
relative superlative.
Let’s see an example of each.
The first of these is an absolute superlative.
It says that Fabio is very good.
There is no specific limit to how good he is.
Notice the suffix, issimo.
The second example is a relative superlative.
This is because his talent is limited to his school.
The relative superlative is formed like the
comparative, but with an article in front.
So let’s go back to the absolute superlative.
Let’s practice forming these.
If something is sweet, we would say that it is dolce.
If we want to say that it is very sweet, we
could say molto dolce, but if we want to use
another form of superlative, we could say
that it is dolcissimo.
Let’s try a few more.
That’s how you make superlatives in Italian,
so let’s check comprehension.